Hello everyone and welcome back to Agentic Thinking.
We're once again discussing some more topics around AI, AI systems, how
things are working. Matthias, welcome back.
It's good to see you again.
>> Absolutely.
>> More AI.
>> Yeah, always great to talk more AI.
We, we did a good live reaction show earlier this week.
>> Yes.
>> Now we can take a slightly different pace and go a bit
deeper into things. I hope.
>> If you like funny things, if you like nerds nerding out on
nerdy stuff, go check out our other video.
It's on the channel. I'll make sure I put the link here
in the chat window as well.
And if you'd like to check us out, we did a Mystery
Science Theater 3000 type take on the OpenAI Dev Day announcement.
So we sat down on the bottom screen, we commented, we teased,
we have some fun while they're they're doing the actual event.
So if you find that kind of stuff entertaining and enjoying, we,
we did throw some knowledge in there.
But it is also more about our initial reactions to their product
and their product updates on how they're copying the rest of the
industry at this point. So that's kind of how our feel
>> was indeed absolutely nothing we hadn't seen under a slightly different product
name elsewhere.
>> Right, Exactly. Well, in, in lieu of this, Matias, I'll actually throw
this one, throw this one out there as well.
There was a very funny. I don't know if you saw if
you caught it. The OpenAI team announced these things called dots, little
agents you can go use. Already there had been an announcement made
from Grok or XAI that they had Grokbots.
So it's a bot or it's a dot and lo and behold,
I don't know if you know this, Xai went out and bought
the domain dot.com bought it and then when you go to dot.com
it actually routes you over to Grokbot and lets you see all
the Grokbots. They took the domain name of dot.com away, they had
it, but like they bought it quick, quickly stuck a website behind
it and made a whole bunch of Grox behind it to kind
of tease, I guess, open AI and copy in their name and
their schema, which they look exactly like the same product.
Honestly, did you hear about this?
>> I did not. But it's hilarious and funny to me.
Yeah.
>> What happens when billionaires play with money and start, you know, picking
at each other with their businesses?
Oh my goodness.
>> Anyways, reminds me of the old days when Microsoft managed to get.
As their landing domain for Net.
So that was pretty cool.
Sometimes you have to be lucky and quick in the first, right?
>> Yes, most certainly. The link, if you want to see that whole
video is in the chat window here.
I'll put that there for anyone who wants to go check it
out on another time. All right, let's talk about our main topic.
So main topic for today is Rust.
What the heck is Rust? And the reason I think we are
bringing this up is if you look at the recent news article,
there's a number of different platforms that are rebuilding their infrastructure solely
in this new I guess it's a programming language called Rust.
GitHub Copilot now runs on Rust.
Bun is another program that now runs on Rust.
There's a lot of conversation around that.
Codex is doing a rewrite in rust, but surprisingly TypeScript 7 is
not. Let's unpack this concept. Matthias, you're way better in the coding
space that I am. Let's give our audience a little bit of
a run up on what the heck is Rust and why do
we care about it. Compared to other things,
>> it's a programming language relatively young.
It went 1.0 in 2015 and was originally developed by Mozilla, still
remember that those days.
And it basically promises to give you C C performance.
Without the disadvantages of hardcore C C.
And so the key thing
from my point of view is it allows you to produce native
binaries on any system you compile for you don't have an intermediary.
Most other languages, TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, NET, Java, all of these run
on a
runtime that does some type of
on the fly compilation on the target machine,
which makes it very, very portable.
But it obviously comes at a huge cost with respect to actually
not getting native performance. And Rust does not have that problem.
Rust also is very strict from a static typing point of view,
which is actually brilliant when it comes to producing huge non trivial
code bases. And I think that's the reason those two points together,
the static typing strictness as well as the
native code combination targets you get, I think that's what makes it
particularly interesting nowadays. And obviously one of the big disadvantages a language
like Rust or C would have had previously.
It's quite complex and difficult for human developers.
Writing stuff in Python or TypeScript is substantially easier.
But we no longer have that problem now, obviously because humans basically
don't write code anymore. And so you know that that problem completely
goes away because you pretty much sort of get the code writing
expertise for free just by handing stuff out to agents.
But you get, you get all the other benefits.
So personally, you know, I'm actually producing a lot of my own
projects in Rust these days. So I'm really.
Oh man,
I can't remember the last time I've done anything in.
Net, which used to be my big thing.
I know by myself, a NET developer that's out of the window.
I converted From. NET to TypeScript at some point and now I'm
actually even bigger convert to Rust.
When I saw, and coming back to the topic here, when I
saw this very, very big September blog article about GitHub's Rust migration,
I saw lots of common touch points there.
>> Let's go a little bit deeper here.
Yes, I think there's some really interesting.
I feel like there's a couple interesting concepts that we're unpacking here.
One is when I don't write code anymore, I'm not really required
to like learn a particular language and stick with it anymore.
Right. So it's, it's less hard, it's less difficult for me to
like pick what's the best solution.
There may be some trade offs, there may be some advantages in
one language or another. There always is.
And how the different languages run.
And now you can kind of start without requiring the years of
knowledge, of learning, like all the nuances of how Rust works.
You can now lean on your agents because they already know how
to run it. They already know how to write perfect code.
In Rust, the function may not do what you want, but the
function will run every single time.
There's other concepts here that I think you still have to be
mindful of. We're not saying throw out languages and just pick whatever
you want and go everything. With Rust, I think we're just saying
that the barrier to be able to write in any language is
minimal. I was doing an experiment a number of months ago, probably
about three months ago now. Just build a project.
I just told the agent, hey, I want to build this project.
Here's my concept, here's my idea.
It was around token generation on my computer, locally on local computer
code gen with large language models.
I wanted to download models, I wanted to have it run it's
terminal command line interface. And I added the simple requirement, write this
thing 100% in Rust. I don't want anything else built in anything
not Rust. And it said sure.
And it did the whole thing.
Built the binaries, I had code, I had files I could download.
So I was able to actually download the actual executable, run it
on my machine and everything ran like Clockwork.
Now there could have been things that I should have been looking
at and being mindful of, but it was my experiment in can
I just describe the system that I desire and then say, oh,
by the way, drop it in this type of language?
And it did a good job.
It didn't take it too long to actually noodle through what I
needed to be built inside Rust.
Now, side project I put on the shelf.
I'm not playing with it right now, but this is, I think,
the ease of what we're doing here.
So let's unpack. Is there Anything in the GitHub article?
So I'll put the GitHub article here in the chat window, which
by the
>> way, is a gigantic article.
>> Huge.
>> Give yourself some quiet space and some time to read it or
give it
>> to your agent and tell it to summarize it.
>> Interesting. If you look into the header of the article right at
the top, it says 65 minutes reading time.
>> Oh, wow. Yeah, it's a bit of a, a mind bender.
>> So we're definitely not going to recite it back to you right
now.
>> Absolutely not. But maybe we can pick out a couple things.
Is there anything that specifically Matisse, that stood out to you that
you maybe would highlight in here around, you know, part of this
process?
>> Well, number one, absolutely. How deep and comprehensive this article is and
into how much detail they've gone here to explain what they've done.
The article is about the GitHub copilot runtime, which is not open
source, so it's quite interesting. So they're talking about a project that
no one outside of GitHub will ever see in terms of what's
actually come out of it. So
you can't really test anything they're claiming here.
You can't check that it's not an open source project.
It also appears as if the human involvement in that conversion project
was very, very limited. So the author, Stephen, appears to have run
the whole project more or less on his own.
And then he gives credit to a handful of people who made
some contributions. Everything else seems to have been agent driven, including I
think somewhere, if I don't,
if I'm remember correctly, I, I, I have.
Yeah, there we go. 830,000 lines of, of, of Rust code came
out of it. Yeah, yeah.
Plus almost half a million lines of Rust unit.
So we're talking, you know, a pretty very, very substantial project in
terms of quantity. And
it's been going on, according to the article since May.
And they give, you know, all the reasons why they've done that
and
obviously one of the main drivers, so they've come from a TypeScript
code base and one of the main drivers really was that they
wanted the Copilot engine to be as portable as possible, but also
as performant as possible and they want to be able to embed
it into all kinds of other products.
And so that embedding story in particular, if you, if you were
relying on a TypeScript code base, would require for you to have
some sort of node or JavaScript runtime embedded there, which is obviously
not ideal. Ideal, if you're thinking, I don't know, Excel or desktop
or stuff like that. Right, yes.
So being able to actually compile into native code, as I explained
in the beginning, you know, makes a massive difference in addition to
all the performance benefits you're going to get from that.
>> Interesting. Yeah, this is really neat because this is.
So I'm going to project a little bit here.
This is totally speculation at this point.
Right. This step needs to happen before the announcement of now the
new unified co pilot like experience that Microsoft is touting.
And you know, so the, the term co pilot is I think
very overweighted just in general. Right.
I go to Microsoft 365. I hear the word copilot, I go
to fabric, I hear the word copilot, I hear GitHub and I
hear the word copilot. While these are the same words, Matthias, you
and I know behind the scenes, the bits that run each of
those in portable places, they're all different.
It's all different fractured code bases.
I liken the analogy. For those of you who are in the
data science or the Power BI world, it's like Power Query.
Power Query has three different layers of bits right now.
One layer of bits is in Excel, one layer of bits is
in Power BI Desktop. Another layer of bits is in power bi.com
they all have. It's the same product.
You still say Power Query in all instances, but they all are
slightly, a little bit different. Some of them have had newer updates,
some of them have not. I think this is maybe an attempt
to say, look, now that we have this ultra portable framework that
has been rebuilt off of TypeScript, we've removed some dependencies.
It's now a self compiled binary.
We can just lift it everywhere we want.
To me this feels like a precursor to hey, let's announce a
unified copilot experience where we're using all the best things that came
from GitHub Copilot and now we're putting it anywhere in the Organization.
This feels like it fits with the story, the broader story of
build once, reuse everywhere. And I think this is what we're going
to continue to see is I even see it in my own
software right now. Everything I'm thinking about and maybe a part of
this article that's, that's pulled out here that I think is important
is one, there's a human role to software development, right?
The architecture tests, how do you migrate?
When do you tell agents to stop doing something and start doing
something else? The direction piece here, that still is paramount in what
they're doing with this rust rebuild.
And that human role, I believe, is what I'm using now more
in my software. I'm looking more comprehensively across multiple products, multiple pieces,
and saying, I think I see the same thing being used multiple
times. For example, my ui, I build lots of workloads in fabric,
I build apps and websites. But I want all of it to
feel the same. I want to look the same.
So I'm stopping building the individual product.
And I'm starting to say, okay, agents, I need you to help
think with me. How do I build reusable components of things as
I build software that I'm having fun with?
Some of them need to have paywalls.
Well, you can build one piece of software with a paywall in
it, but what do you need to have that paywall reused in
other pieces of software? There's a lot of common structural pieces that
you want to reuse or build or enhance so that, you know,
today my paywall uses Venmo. Well, maybe I want to add to
that PayPal or add to that something new, or maybe Xpay is
going to be one you're going to want.
Like, I don't know, who knows what the future holds, but I
need a package in which I could leverage paywalls across multiple parts
of products. So my paywall right now that I'm building on the
side is a mix of crypto payments.
So you can go buy your things with Solana and you can
actually use your wallet to pay for things in real software as
well as, okay, well, maybe you want to use Venmo instead, right?
So pick, pick your payment provider and you can pay for things
both ways, fully realizing that today everything's Venmo, but in the future
we're going to have a lot more agents, bots, crypto experiences that
are going to be paying for things.
I want to be prepared for that.
I want to have software that can easily adapt to one place
or the other. What are Your thoughts on this, Matthias?
>> Right.
>> Well, what you're seeing as well.
>> Yeah, I guess what you're talking about is good old software architecture,
right? Thinking about, you know, high level architecture, what am I aiming
for? How do I create components that contribute to a bigger system?
How do I reuse components? None of that has gone away, right?
You know, we may no longer be writing, you know, the individual
lines of code, but we still have the job to get things
like architecture and vision and
to some degree testing, right?
If, if I guess from my point of view that's the big
difference. But between using agents to produce software and wipe coding, if
you're a vibe coder, you don't think about anything like that, right?
You just create a big prompt and then you're happy when something
comes back. And it may well look pretty, but what kind of
lifetime will it have, right?
What happens when something breaks or when you want new features?
Is that even going to be viable?
With good software architecture you don't have those problems, right?
This is where you design and build for longevity and maintainability.
So that comes to mind and
in a way we can say nowadays we should have much more
headspace and much more freedom to actually invest in things like architecture
and planning because we, we no longer have the burden of writing
code. Right. So
those should be some of the massive amplifiers that we're actually getting
from the agentic world.
Something I wanted to point out, if I may, from the article,
there are a couple of interesting
paragraphs towards the bottom. One of one is a performance comparison.
Very, very, very interesting figures. They're comparing the May version of the
product, which was basically before the migration to an end of August
version, which is pretty much where everything is running in rust.
So one example here, launch a client, create a session and run
one turn before the migration. 5.25 seconds after migration, 18x improvement, 290
milliseconds.
And then another example, resume a existing session that had 32 turns.
May 5.6 seconds. August 21, 20.8 260 milliseconds.
So this is what they've achieved.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah, there we go.
>> Those are huge speed improvements.
>> Yeah, so that is paints a really nice picture.
But the next article is how much did it all cost?
Yes, that's a fun one. And I love how they gone into
some, some great detail here in terms of doing some analysis on
token usage, etc. Etc.
So
they said the total token spend for all the porting work was
136 billion tokens, roughly.
>> Out of which you said 146 billion.
>> Correct. And then 136 and then
130 billion of those were cashed.
Remember we mentioned it a few times.
>> Yeah.
>> The difference between fresh tokens and cash tokens is huge.
From a cost point of view, you always want to make sure
that caching works as. As well as it possibly can because it
will save you enormous amounts of money.
So 130 out of 136 billion were cashed.
But nonetheless, apparently the monetary bill for all of that came to
$120,000, which may seem like a big number, but do think about
how much you'd spend on actual developer hours without agents?
Right.
>> So this is deceiving. I believe.
So. You look at the number like, oh, why would you ever
spend something like that? Right. Let's put this in perspective.
Right. What was the length of this project?
Right.
>> Yeah. Right. So in three months.
>> So three months. Okay, so in three months, full rebuild of something
that is creating anywhere between 12 and 21x increase in speed on
delivery of results. Right. So three months.
If you were going to say no agent, do all of this
with a team of engineers. And this is where I think agents
make things deceiving. And we've talked about this a little bit.
I think, Matthias, is the fact that agents are, are a time
machine. The fact that they can parallelize work, the fact that they
can work when you're not looking at them, the fact that they're
building things outside of your time zone.
Like, you're like, I'm going to go to dinner.
I'm going to give the agent a task.
I'm going to go have dinner and then come back.
And like, I'm doing something, but it's actually building something while I'm
doing something else. It's a time machine.
I would love to understand the area under the curve.
Like, this is almost like we need storyboard points to, to see
what, like, you know, we can measure real storyboard points loosely in
a, in an engineering team and say, okay, this was like, you
know, 300,000 storyboard points of what work was being done.
Right. If we had to put that against a real team, that's
25 engineers working for, you know, six months to a year.
Do this. So we don't have the numbers to quantify this.
If you start pulling the numbers, that actually would have taken a
team of engineers to handwrite all this code without any agents.
We're probably talking millions of dollars.
>> Yeah.
>> Tens of millions, maybe. With all that.
>> Certainly not three months.
>> And the time compression. Yeah. So you're getting two bonuses here.
You're getting a really fast delivery of something.
You're getting a single engineer that is able to architect and direct.
So there's. There's no. Matias, I don't think we should write it
this way because I think the architecture should be A and you're
like, no, architecture should be B.
Because of my experience. Right. There's none of that.
There's one guy at the top saying, this is the architecture.
Figure it out. We're just going to go that direction.
So there's a huge amount of friction, political noise that's being removed
from the system because we build.
We build what's right here. This is wild, in my opinion.
So I want to focus on the area under the curve.
The area under the curve did not change.
The work acquired over time did not change.
It's just the fact that we were able to spend a hundred
thousand dollars in tokens again would be, I think, peanuts compared to
an actual team to get the area of that work completed in
a shorter amount of time as well.
And this is the part that I think is wild to me.
Our minds are having to rethink what does creation of things look
like, because that area or the amount of work.
How would you say this units of work per hour is like
10x100x of where we were previously?
Would you agree with this? Is this conceptually the right direction of
what I should be thinking about here?
>> Totally. I mean, I'm personally experiencing that quite real time vividly at
the moment where I'm continuously running into severe hardware limitations.
You know, I've got a system that is actually so good at
parallelizing that I desperately need to add more hardware to my sort
of built Love IT engine
because
my agent constantly tells me how it's being throttled through cpu, disk
and memory constraints.
>> Wow.
>> So, yeah, that is absolutely true.
And it's, it's a. It's a very nice problem to have because
unfortunately, it's something I can address.
Right. But
again, it just shows we certainly live in different times nowadays.
Anything else comes to mind as far as that one is concerned?
>> No, I think I'm good on this one.
Okay, this one's good. There's really neat article, really like, what's going
on there. Happy that there's a great improvement in performance.
But this is not one company doing this one.
There's more.
>> Yeah. So the other one I wanted to add into the mix
here, BUN was rewritten in Rust.
You see, there's a real theme here that was announced in July,
so early summer, earlier this year.
>> What is bun? Let's talk about what is BUN so people can
understand. I got another framework, but like what is bun?
>> Right? So bun is an alternative JavaScript runtime.
So it's an alternative to node.
In fact, it's actually more than just a runtime.
BUN is also a package manager and a test runner.
So BUN is basically. BUN replaces NODE and NPM and VITE in
a way, or VTest, let's say VTest.
If you think you don't need Node, you don't need npm, you
don't need vtest, because you've got this alternative system that is basically
all of that. And basically BUN implements the
node APIs, but
in a sort of, they would claim better and faster way.
And
earlier this year they decided to rewrite the whole thing in Rust.
I think the reasons for that are pretty clear based on what
we said earlier. And BUN became very, very well known and popular
for one reason I would say in, in, in, in circles, you
know, where people wouldn't have been aware of it already because CLAUDE
code, the Claude CLI was built on top of BUN from the
beginning. And so this is actually how many people
have heard of BUN if they hadn't already.
And so you won't be surprised to Hear that in December 25,
Anthropic actually acquired Bunch. You know, it was a relatively small community
driven project, Anthropic, you know, that's when they had loads of money
to spend from all the
VC money they'd collected. Given that they had such a massive dependency
on bun, you know, for, for their Claude cli.
They just acquired the whole thing, it looks like, I mean, to
me, as someone who is been following the BUN project for a
while, it looks like they've had certainly substantially less frequent releases since.
So it's a bit sad. But the, the Rust rewrite was certainly
a big one. And again, we've got an article from the BUN
block in the show Notes here where they talk about that rewrite
and
apparently. So that's actually, that's. That's a rewrite from Zigzag, which is
yet another language also quite sort of close to C
Z from my point of view, definitely a bit more of an
obscure language.
So that's where they've come from.
And yeah, if you want to see more about it in terms
of stats and performance improvements and all of that, look at the
article we've provided here. So ever since v1.4,
bun is written in Rust and
another project I Thought would be quite useful to share is TypeScript
7.
>> Oh, okay. So. So everything up to this point, we've been talking
about everyone moving to Rust. Rust is like, oh, let's go do
everything in Rust. Thorough agents at it build things.
Okay, TypeScript 7 did any vowel against Rust and they chose not
to use it. So
this is good to understand why you didn't do something just as
well as why you did do something.
So what's the converse of this?
What did they pick?
>> So TypeScript went with go instead of Rust.
So just to understand the context here.
Right, so famously Typescript
has always been built in Typescript all the way up to V6.
So ever since at the very beginning, I mean, obviously there's a
hen and egg problem here, but at some point they had a
sort of very minimal TypeScript compiler and then they used that one
to then actually build the TypeScript project itself.
Sounds weird, right? And so presumably the compiler itself would always have
been slightly ahead of the main version of the project.
Right. And
that became a real bottleneck actually, in terms of the compiler performance.
Because, you know, whilst TypeScript as a language is incredibly developer friendly
and flexible and very
good because of its typing constructs, it's not really
great for performance, particularly when you're talking multimillion lines of code code,
project. And so they ran into some real performance
constraints when it comes to compiling projects like VS code, for instance,
versus code. Obviously TypeScript code base.
Millions and millions of lines of code that compiling vs code before
v7 used to take a big machine.
And a lot of time
they had to make a call at some point to give up
that very neat foundation of saying TypeScript is using TypeScript to build
itself and to actually go and build the TypeScript compiler and something
else. There's a very nice interview, you can watch that on YouTube
with Anderson, the creator of TypeScript who talks all about the.
The V7
conversion, you know, how they achieved more than 10x improvement, how they
used the versus code code base in particular, you know, as a
significant benchmark there.
And so he was asked how did they end up with Go?
And he very clearly says Rust was a serious contender and definitely
something they
looked at. But so his main argument, I'm paraphrasing it, but he's
basically saying they didn't. They wanted to port the TypeScript code base,
they didn't want to rewrite it, they wanted, they wanted to go
to a different language, but they wanted to go to a language
that in terms of sort of the, the primitives of the language
and sort of the similar. The philosophy of it and, and the
semantics was really close to Typescript and Rust is not that, you
know, whereas Go on the other hand is.
And so he basically said going to go.
They didn't quite get exactly the same
performance improvements that hypothetically they would have achieved with Rust, but they
had the massive advantage of being able to do a port, you
know, where basically you do a syntactic conversion of your code base
instead of a complete semantic rewrite of it.
And as you can imagine, you know, that ultimately is a very
sort of pragmatic way of deciding that.
And yeah, if you want Anders to explain in his words, which
are substantially better than mine, go and watch that video there.
>> My brain hears this stuff and this is very intriguing to me.
I'm very interested in this. While I don't do code, I'm very
interested in the architecture decisions and why we do things and how
long it takes things to get done.
That stuff is very applicable and I think very useful for us
to study. Right. What these really smart teams are doing and just
to unpack what they're doing. One of the things that makes me
really so one in this TypeScript 7 article, there's some beautiful, some
beautiful diagrams showing you how much faster it is versus TypeScript 6
versus TypeScript 7. So definitely check out the article.
That's the one I just recently posted here.
You definitely want to work on this one.
One of the things I'll notice here.
Let's talk about VS code. And it's 2.3 million lines of code
to make it right. I just want to unpack that for a
minute.
Whatever machine they're using, it compiled in 125 seconds before.
Now it's in 10.6 seconds to compile now.
So this is an 11, almost 11.9 to be precise, but almost
a 12x speed increase. Now I'm going to pick on you a
bit here, Matthias, because I think this is a good point to
talk about. When you have big projects, when you have lots of
code running, the amount of time it takes the code to compile
basically turns into real dollars.
This is because a lot of my development cycle, and I believe
yours is too, is now running inside GitHub and GitHub has runners,
and runners are action based. I commit something to my main branch.
I'm ready to compile some code, I'm ready to produce the output
of whatever the thing is, doesn't really matter.
I'm building a static website and I have a whole bunch of
pages on this. If I can get the code to compile 5%,
10% faster. The more we work with agents, the more commits we're
making to code. So, so what's happening right now, and the theory
I think is what's going on here is the volume of creation
with agents is rapidly increasing. We've seen this with GitHub's usage through
the roof, like everyone's building code.
My GitHub if your GitHub page, right?
So on your GitHub page you have all these little like the
square graph, right? It's every day.
How many commits have you made or changes of code?
My graph, all the old code that I did in 2015, actually
even earlier 2016, probably like January.
Those colors look almost dark now.
My GitHub illustration now is very green, very bright green.
Because the amount of code I'm pushing directly to GitHub has greatly
improved, greatly sped up with agents.
There's a couple compounding factors. More code is being written than ever.
More commits are happening than ever.
If you combine those two together.
More actions, more time, more computers are running.
We know in the data space that storage is cheap.
Storing the files on GitHub is almost nothing.
But compute is expensive. Anytime I want to spin up a vm,
a machine, an action that's spending real money, and we only get,
as a GitHub user, a certain amount of minutes before you have
to start paying for them, it costs you real money.
You know, you've hit your threshold this month.
Me personally, I set an upper limit threshold for the Carlo Solutions
organization On how many GitHub action minutes I needed.
We ran into that, we ran into the limit and I had
to up the limit because we're doing so much more production of
work across my team that I need more minutes of actions to
continue to compile code.
This is, I think, a real concept and I really like improvements
like this where we're ripping out 10x20x25x time of code compilation need.
Because this turns into real money.
And if you're on an old code base, this is going to
encourage you to move from six to seven.
Because if you have a lot of code lines in Typescript, this
is real money that you're leaving on the table at this point.
>> Right. Ultimately, it's about feedback loops.
If you're in a code base and you make a change, you
want to be able to get feedback from the system with respect
to
does it compile, does it pass my tests?
Right? Yes. If running your Test Suite takes 25 minutes each time
you're not going to have
a good experience there, you're going to wait ages.
That's been true forever. Right.
When humans were writing code and you had a poor build system
or a slow developer machine and you had to wait ages, it
really impacted your productivity. The same is true with agents, but even
more so because
you usually have multiple of them going at once, right.
Rather than just one at a time.
So absolutely, very true. And
that also. So, yeah, so that's one thing.
So being able to actually get
something to compile and tell you whether or not it compiles is
one step. By the way, this is also where language servers come
in, right? LSP
a big deal inside the VS code ecosystem, where you've got language
servers running in the background that basically are able to
understand
files containing code semantically and in particular they are able to understand
snippets of them rather than an entire code base at once.
You know the language server protocol and the language server ecosystem VS
code is addressing directly that issue.
It's. It's there to give you very quick feedback, right?
>> Yes.
>> You've. You made modifications to a particular function.
The language server is able to
give you immediate feedback even if the project itself doesn't build, right?
>> Yes, correct. You don't want to get the build time to find
there's a problem. You want to find the problem much earlier in
the process. And I'm going to maybe ask a question here because
I don't understand this one or know about this one language server
protocol, the lsps that is that now being exposed directly to agentic
development experiences like particularly so like, you know, as the agent is
writing its own code inside your code base, those LSP notifications or
things that's coming back to the agent and say, hey, you wrote
a function, it's not real, the syntax is wrong.
Then the agent is immediately picking that up and then able to.
Oh yes, you're right, I'll fix the thing.
>> CLAUDE code added. I'm just quickly googling it here while some talking.
They added native support for LSP a long time ago.
>> Yes, exactly.
>> That is something which is in the harness.
But I am here. There we go.
So I can see an article which is dated June 26th
>> as a version 2.047 Claude code has native server language server protocol
support, which is good. But this is my point that my point
is more and more software development tooling is now being geared more
towards the agent. How does the agent see this?
How does the agent write things?
And then all These other Stan, like we would still use it
like humans would still look at it in VS code and say,
oh, there's now a red squiggly line under this function because something
wasn't defined correctly or you added a parameter that doesn't need to
be there or just syntactically, something was wrong.
We need to see that. But now, more importantly, the agents also
need to see that as well.
>> If you think about this architecturally, right.
Without that, your LLM obviously does next token prediction, right.
When it looks at some code, it basically ultimately does pattern matching
and tries to figure out given sort of a vast amount of
learned examples,
How is your code snippet most likely to modify to sort of
match some of the good examples that they've learned from.
Right. Whereas using an LSP adds a level of semantics that the
LLM per se does not have at all, even though it always
appears to us if there's intelligence.
Right. But the sort of bringing an LSP into the mix would
be able to identify, for instance, this particular token happens to be
a function name. And ASP can know that, but an LLM cannot.
Right?
>> Yes.
>> So stuff like that.
>> Exactly. It's like an additional layer of context you're giving to the
agent as it's building things. And as I unpack some of this,
I'm having an aha moment here around like okay one, all this
makes sense. But you know, when large language models are trying to
write you functions, it's statistically I think the term would be is
like you're regressing to the mean.
You're going to like the most common function that you're trying to
write. And this is brings the phrase to my mind like nothing's
new under the sun. Right. There's every function I need to write
in my program. Someone has probably already written a similar like function
in some other program and in some other language that is the
ideal or the most performant way to write that function.
So large language models are just trying to regress to what is
the most common observation that I see about your particular function.
So nothing's unique. But now the LSP being part of this pattern,
you don't need to regress to the mean.
You can build what you need to build and get the syntax
right. So it's almost like a good.
This feels like a harness, major harness improvement.
>> Oh yeah.
>> To allow the agent to not have to be so rigid around
regressing to the same function that everyone writes over and over again.
Now we can be a bit more creative and still get the
right output that we desire.
>> What I find very interesting though is as we're talking about this
and how coding agent harnesses and LSPs or should be, you know,
theoretically a very, very good combo.
Weirdly enough, one, I don't think the announcement of CLAUDE code adding
native LSP support has been received as big as it should be,
nor does it appear to be as big a feature even today
as it should be, given what we just said.
>> Right.
>> If you Google CLAUDE and lsp, you're not even going to find
any top hits that go directly to the CLAUDE code documentation, for
instance. So it's a bit of a weird one, which I can't
really make sense of. Maybe some smarter people can comment on that.
It feels like it would be a perfect match, but somehow it's
not. Maybe we're missing something here in terms of harness development.
Or maybe the LLMs are so good now that the extra help
from LSP is no longer needed.
>> Who knows? Or maybe we didn't even know, like, you know, Right.
Yeah, we, we're just talking heads at this point, looking at observations
of like, how we see and how we're interacting with agents in
the world here and what we're building.
And again, we all have different.
Everyone's going to have different degrees of, of use and discoverability what's
going on here. So I hope you enjoyed this discussion.
I think this is a probably a good moment here to kind
of like wrap and kind of wind down here a little bit.
I think we had some really good discussion.
I'm very encouraged by seeing software being entirely rewritten in these new
languages. That's very exciting to me, seeing other companies do this at
scales that I'm not able to do myself personally in my company,
I'm not going to spend $100,000 on any kind of rewrite of
software. But I think this is starting to set patterns in the
cost and rewrite world that now we're able to observe.
Like this is possible. You know, you, you build an app today
on a framework that is what you make the best decisions around
today. This really drops the barrier for you.
Well, to me, it minimizes the risk of picking the wrong language
to start with on a project.
You can build a project. Let's say we build, go for a
couple years. AI is just going to get better and maybe you
decide at some point in the future.
No, we should have gone and gone down the rust route.
That's what we wanted. Okay, put Matias on it for three weeks
and, and spend, you know, 50,000 in tokens and get the rewrite.
Okay, not a problem. Does this also mean at some point in
the future where we say, well, we think it's going to be
these three languages. We narrow down three languages that we like the
best. Okay, great. Build all three at the same time.
And then you evaluate and monitor performance of all three at the
same time. The lower you bring the barrier of cost down and
the shorter you bring the time down, that just means less risk
to you as you build. The thing is how I'm perceiving it
anyways. That being said, Matias, this has been a great conversation.
I have many points I'm going to have to chew on and
think about now. We hope you enjoyed this conversation as well.
This show is highly technical, so if you haven't learned this already,
we're going to talk about things that are deep and things that
are, that are at the high level.
But, but there needs to be some level of forum, public communication
forum around this kind of topic.
I think this is relevant banter that we should educate ourselves on.
Like we need like, like this kind of language.
So if there's other topics that you like, if there's other things
that are interesting to you, please let us know down in the
comments if you found this content valuable.
We really appreciate it. If you give us a thumbs up, just
let us know with some feedback there.
We'd love to have a thumbs up on the video.
It helps us know that this is content that you like.
We'll continue making it. You don't, that's fine, no problem.
We can, you know, don't give us a thumbs up.
But if you also want to be notified of any new updates
or conversations we're having between this or explicit measures or any other
content, there's also a subscribe button.
We'd love you to hit that as well.
Matias, thank you so much. Another great conversation.
This has been wonderful. We'll see you all next time.
>> Thank you.
>> Hopefully my surprise will work. It's been a little slow to play
here. Let's see if it'll see if it'll run here.
Maybe
come on app, figure yourself out
>> the suspense is killing me.
>> I've been trying to add music at the end of our videos.
>> Sam.
Monday memo says accelerate burn the tokens don't you hesitate Dashboards watching
every prompt you send Use too little and you're at the end
Secret agents, secret agents Building systems in the basement Secret age agents
under the radar Just trying not to get the paper.
Tuesday memo flips the script again
Talking budgets bleeding cut it then Same old boss with a brand
new fear Yesterday's hero is old over here Secret agents Secret agents
Building systems in the basement Secret agents under the radar Just trying
not to get up the paper
so we spit up tools they never blessed Shadow stack to survive
the test by sea for Claude when the gate gets closed by
sea for Grok when the path gets froze More tokens, less tokens
make up your mind where solving work they leave behind unsanctioned Ain't
the dream we chose it's the only way the deadline goes.
Business users in a quiet war sanction path don't open anymore if
the company can't decide the lane Secret agents keep us in the
game Secret agents, Secret agents Building systems in the basement Secret agents
under the radar Just trying not to get the paper Secret agents.
Under the radar.
Sam.